<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[Random notes and thoughts.]]></description><link>https://thomas6188.github.io/blog</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 12:25:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[2025 in Review (Unpublished)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This post is currently under construction.]]></description><link>https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/year-in-review-2025/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/year-in-review-2025/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 22:40:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This post is currently under construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.tenor.com/K5wSW-CGK9wAAAAi/maintenance-under-maintenance.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Under Construction&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Don't be a Crow (Unpublished)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This post is currently under construction.]]></description><link>https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/dont-be-crow/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/dont-be-crow/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This post is currently under construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.tenor.com/K5wSW-CGK9wAAAAi/maintenance-under-maintenance.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Under Construction&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Thousand Splendid Likes (Unpublished)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This post is currently under construction.]]></description><link>https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/workspace/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/workspace/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This post is currently under construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.tenor.com/K5wSW-CGK9wAAAAi/maintenance-under-maintenance.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Under Construction&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[C4 Model of Life (Unpublished)]]></title><description><![CDATA[This post is currently under construction.]]></description><link>https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/c4-model-life/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/c4-model-life/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This post is currently under construction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.tenor.com/K5wSW-CGK9wAAAAi/maintenance-under-maintenance.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Under Construction&quot; style=&quot;max-width: 100%; height: auto;&quot;&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title><description><![CDATA[About Me Hi there. I am an AI-native software engineer from Kerala, India. I graduated in 2010 with a bachelor's degree in Information…]]></description><link>https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://thomas6188.github.io/blog/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;About Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi there. I am an AI-native software engineer from Kerala, India. I graduated in 2010 with a bachelor&apos;s degree in Information Technology. I have 14+ years of experience in SharePoint and M365 space, with focus on cloud and related technologies- Copilot and Gen AI, SharePoint Online, Power Platform, Azure, React and TypeScript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began my career as a SharePoint developer in 2011. In those days, everything was on-premises, and building custom components required a SharePoint Server for both development and deployment. One incorrect logic or memory leak could bring down the entire SharePoint farm. God bless the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hobbies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;u&gt;Science and Tech&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My love for tech started during my high school days when I read a magazine called The Chip. While growing up, I didn&apos;t have access to Internet, so this magazine was my gateway to the world of gadgets, apps, and technology in general. &lt;br&gt;
The first personal computer I had was a Pentium 3 Desktop, with 48 MB RAM. This was my lab for trying out a new OS, apps, and games. I still remember making a scene at home so that my parents can buy me an additional RAM module because Win XP won&apos;t install on machine that has less than 64 MB RAM 😞. Today, 15 years later, nothing has changed for me except the medium- Reddit and HackerNews have replaced the print magazine. I still get excited when I see a new product launch, a new breakthrough or a discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;u&gt;Food and Travel&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing I believe when it comes to Food and Travel is that it should never be a forced activity. It is best enjoyed alone or with people you like. Instagram or Facebook posts shouldn&apos;t be the deciding factor, your fondness for the people, place, and food should.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Recent memorable trip: Singapore.&lt;br&gt;
Wishlist: Japan, Euro Trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;u&gt;Books&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/6098066-thomas-mathew&quot;&gt;https://www.goodreads.com/review/list/6098066-thomas-mathew&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;u&gt;Movies and Television&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Genre: Action, Comedy, Romance, and Sci-fi. Basically, anything except Horror.&lt;br&gt;
TV Shows: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/list/ls073361911/&quot;&gt;https://www.imdb.com/list/ls073361911/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;u&gt;Sports&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Cricket&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to be an avid Cricket fan. Like every Indian, I would be glued to my television when the Indian team was playing. Sachin&apos;s Desert Storm in Sharjah is still etched in my memory, even though it has been more than 25 years. With the introduction of IPL, the sport has become more commercialized and my excitement for it has diminished. Now, I just watch the Ashes and World Cup events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;Formula 1&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A sport that I follow regularly these days is Formula 1. My interest piqued (and I assume it did for a lot of people) thanks to the Netflix series Drive to Survive. At present, I don’t have a favorite team or driver, as I am still figuring out the different rules, strategies, and technicalities involved in a race weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h5&gt;WWE&lt;/h5&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If there is one guilty pleasure I have, it&apos;s WWE (if you count it as sport). Back in the day, it was known as WWF. The matches and storylines we have now cannot hold a candle to what we had during the Attitude Era. With the passage of time, and as I grew older, the thrill for the sport fizzled out. Although, I do enjoy major annual events such as WrestleMania, in the hope that I get to see some of the old WWE Hall of Famers. Steve Austin&apos;s entrance music still rocks, and if you agree, gimme a &apos;Hell yeah!&apos;😎
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>